<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://vxsan.com/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copy, _right?_ :thinking_face:</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 04:12:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vxsan.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rapid deployment of K3S on vSphere using K3OS</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/rapid-deployment-of-k3s-on-vsphere-using-k3os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 04:12:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/rapid-deployment-of-k3s-on-vsphere-using-k3os/</guid><description>No fluff here, just a quick writeup of how to rapidly deploy a multimaster kubernetes cluster using K3OS on vSphere. This can probably be done even faster by remastering ISOs, using packer or cloud-init directly to the VM but that&amp;rsquo;s something for the future.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://vxsan.com/posts/rapid-deployment-of-k3s-on-vsphere-using-k3os/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Letsencrypt Certificate automation with NSX Advanced Load Balancer</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/letsencrypt-certificate-automation-with-nsx-advanced-load-balancer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 04:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/letsencrypt-certificate-automation-with-nsx-advanced-load-balancer/</guid><description>As part of a bit of a cleanup at home, i&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move all my services behind a single centralised loadbalancer, which at this point happens to AVI just so i can get more day to day experience with it.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://vxsan.com/posts/letsencrypt-certificate-automation-with-nsx-advanced-load-balancer/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Manageable micro-segmentation with the consumer-provider architecture</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/manageable-micro-segmentation-with-the-consumer-provider-architecture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 04:16:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/manageable-micro-segmentation-with-the-consumer-provider-architecture/</guid><description>This blogpost discusses how the consumer-provider microsegmentation model works, its strengths and weaknesses, and why you might want to consider using this for your future micro-segmentation strategies.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://vxsan.com/posts/manageable-micro-segmentation-with-the-consumer-provider-architecture/featured.jpg"/></item><item><title>VCF Microsegmentation, the right way</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/vcf-microsegmentation-right-way/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 17:43:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/vcf-microsegmentation-right-way/</guid><description>In some recent engagements i&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in getting my customers started with a microsegmentations strategy, and one of the more obvious requests from people new to microsegmentation is to start with their infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>VRLCM &amp; vRA prerequisites in a locked down environment</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-vra-deployment-locked-down-environment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 06:10:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-vra-deployment-locked-down-environment/</guid><description>A very brief one, but for a current project i&amp;rsquo;m working on LCM in a heavily locked down environment. So locked down in fact that even RDP to the servers is impossible, which makes making changing slightly impractical as everything has to go through the console.</description></item><item><title>Scripted modification of vRA reservations with powerVRA.</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/scripted-vra-reservations-powervra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 08:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/scripted-vra-reservations-powervra/</guid><description>Recently, a customer of mine needed to modify a large number of vRA reservations to facilitate a migration, and because there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with being lazy, using powershell is always one of my go-to options.</description></item><item><title>Running pre-boot, post-provisioning vRO workflows in vRA.</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/running-pre-boot-vro-workflows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 10:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/running-pre-boot-vro-workflows/</guid><description>Note: As this is more of a reminder for myself so i don&amp;rsquo;t forget next time, don&amp;rsquo;t expect too much fluff.
Last week i needed to demonstrate how to temporarily enable firewall rules using the NSX DFW for a customer use case that is pretty serious about zero trust policies.</description></item><item><title>Building a NSX-T nested lab part 2</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/building-a-nsx-t-nested-lab-part-2-electric-boogaloo-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 12:04:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/building-a-nsx-t-nested-lab-part-2-electric-boogaloo-part-1/</guid><description>if you&amp;rsquo;ve read my previous blog post about NSX-T, you should know the basics of what NSX-T does and why it&amp;rsquo;s the best thing since mankind invented rocket surgery. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll try to give you a brief overview of the steps to take to deploy NSX-T in your lab environment the easy way.</description></item><item><title>A brief thank you to the tech community</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/a-brief-thank-you-to-the-vcommunity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 03:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/a-brief-thank-you-to-the-vcommunity/</guid><description>note: header image shameless stolen from XKCD . Credit where credit is due
Once upon a time - as any good story is supposed to begin - people were working in IT.</description></item><item><title>Ansible-Vault password management made easy with Lastpass-CLI and Rake</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/ansible-vault-passwords-done-easy-with-lastpass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 06:30:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/ansible-vault-passwords-done-easy-with-lastpass/</guid><description>With a fresh new year comes a fresh new set of VPS hosts, and as a resolution i&amp;rsquo;m planning to fully deploy these through ansible, along with migrating a lot of my existing machines to ansible as well.</description></item><item><title>Surviving the sandpit - week 1</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/surviving-the-sandpit-week-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 11:22:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/surviving-the-sandpit-week-1/</guid><description>As most of you are probably aware by now, i&amp;rsquo;ve moved to Dubai to work for VMware. By now, it&amp;rsquo;s been a bit over a week so i thought i might as well provide everyone back at home (or wherever you are) with an update.</description></item><item><title>Burn down your DFW onboarding with vRealize Log Insight</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/burn-down-your-dfw-onboarding-process-with-log-insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 08:05:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/burn-down-your-dfw-onboarding-process-with-log-insight/</guid><description>Currently i&amp;rsquo;m working on a NSX project involving a large amount of networks and a complicated firewall setup that needs to be migrated to NSX. Using tools such as vRealize Network insight for traffic flow insight helps a lot, but ultimately the DFW onboarding process needs to be SMART, and specifically the following:</description></item><item><title>Privacy policy</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 06:03:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/privacy-policy/</guid><description>No personal data - outside of tracking cookies for personal stats monitoring - is processed on this site. This tracking data is processed by my personal statistics and analysis system and is for personal usage and optimisation of this website.</description></item><item><title>New layout!</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/new-layout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 14:31:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/new-layout/</guid><description>A fresh new ghost installation means a fresh new layout. It&amp;rsquo;s currently partially under development, but most features should be working. So if you have any feedback, bugs, items that aren&amp;rsquo;t working or any other criticism, i&amp;rsquo;d be glad to hear it.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Log Insight : pre-classifying events for SIEM</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/vrli-preclassify-filter-events-for-siem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 06:06:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/vrli-preclassify-filter-events-for-siem/</guid><description>For a project i&amp;rsquo;m currently working on we are using vRealize Log Insight as a logging and monitoring solution. One of the important requirements this customer has is the forwarding of syslog events to HP Arcsight, a SIEM solution.</description></item><item><title>Setting up your own PKI - the simple way</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/setting-up-your-own-pki-the-simple-way/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 11:59:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/setting-up-your-own-pki-the-simple-way/</guid><description>Most of you that are reading this will either have their own lab, or a corporate lab environment, and - most likely - regularly install a variety of vendor products to try out new products, test new features, create demo environments for customers, study for certifications, and more.</description></item><item><title>Building the Virarium 2.0 - or "You know, normal people just have aquariums." - Part 1</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/building-the-virarium-or-you-know-normal-people-have-aquariums-part1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 10:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/building-the-virarium-or-you-know-normal-people-have-aquariums-part1/</guid><description>For those that regularly read XKCD, this one may be familiar for you:
Let me start from the beginning. My previous employer OGD has a yearly event called &amp;ldquo;Technival&amp;rdquo;, which was all about a wild variety of geeky things organised and built by their employees, and the Virarium was the brainchild of me and Robbert Erents .</description></item><item><title>Building a NSX-T nested lab with Eve-NG, virtualised switches, BGP, and the kitchen sink attached.</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/building-a-nsx-t-nested-lab/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 12:23:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/building-a-nsx-t-nested-lab/</guid><description>Since my last tweet and blogpost on a bug in NSX-T when deploying on a nested ESXi host , i&amp;rsquo;ve had a few requests from people to describe the actual lab setup used, the procedure and a quick-and-dirty guide to get started with NSX-T on vSphere.</description></item><item><title>NSX-T Nested ESXi host preparation fails.</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/nsx-t-esxi-host-preparation-fails-errno-1-operation-not-permitted-it-is-not-safe-to-continue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 14:06:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/nsx-t-esxi-host-preparation-fails-errno-1-operation-not-permitted-it-is-not-safe-to-continue/</guid><description>As today was a lab day for the first time in a long while, i decided to finally get around to finishing my NSX-T nested lab.
So after deploying the manager and controller cluster, the time comes to prepare the ESXi hosts.</description></item><item><title>Automated NSX DFW validation with PowerNSX</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/automated-nsx-dfw-validation-with-powernsx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 07:39:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/automated-nsx-dfw-validation-with-powernsx/</guid><description>For a project i&amp;rsquo;m currently working on, we need to provide a full end-to-end validation of the NSX routing, distributed firewall rules and VXLAN functionality. As the amount and complexity of firewall rules are quite significant, i&amp;rsquo;ve written a script that allows you to run and retrieve data from NSX Traceflow in an automated fashion, which can be found at https://bitbucket.</description></item><item><title>VMware Certifications - First steps</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/vmware-certification-first-steps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 10:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/vmware-certification-first-steps/</guid><description>Full Disclosure: This blogpost is written for and part of the VMware vExpert NSX Certification blogging campaign.
A long long time ago when i was still making my first steps in the wonderful world of IT, my role was that of the go-to operations guys for small-medium businesses.</description></item><item><title>multi-backend SSL Passthrough Loadbalancing with VMware NSX</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/multi-backend-ssl-passthrough-loadbalancing-with-nsx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 06:24:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/multi-backend-ssl-passthrough-loadbalancing-with-nsx/</guid><description>Currently i&amp;rsquo;m working on a NSX project that involves automation of NSX loadbalancers to provide loadbalancing as a catalog item. Now, while i would normally prefer deploying dedicated loadbalancers on-demand, a big constraint in this environment is the fact that the ISP takes a significant time to configure the GSLB for new services, so on-demand loadbalancers go straight out of the window.</description></item><item><title>Querying PuppetDB with vRealize Orchestrator and vRealize Automation</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/querying-puppetdb-with-vrealize-orchestrator-and-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:05:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/querying-puppetdb-with-vrealize-orchestrator-and-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>TL;DR: if you&amp;rsquo;re just interested in how to configure orchestrator to allow puppetDB querying, follow the link .
PuppetDB is an extension to Puppet allowing you to aggregate data from Puppet nodes such as custom facts, catalogs and resources.</description></item><item><title>VM deployment &amp; configuration with Puppet and vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/vm-configuration-with-puppet-and-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 02:56:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/vm-configuration-with-puppet-and-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>As you may know, vRealize Automation 7 brought us a great deal of improvements, one of which is the composite blueprint and the software components. With the new release of vRA 7.</description></item><item><title>Puppet 4 lookup &amp; hiera node classification</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/puppet-4-lookup-hiera-node-classification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 13:57:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/puppet-4-lookup-hiera-node-classification/</guid><description>As i was working with some of the new puppet 4 functions, i noticed that most documentation for node classification still refers to hiera_include for the purpose of node classification and class inclusion.</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI 6.5R1 brings some amazing new automation features</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/powercli-6-5r1-brings-some-amazing-new-automation-features/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 17:08:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/powercli-6-5r1-brings-some-amazing-new-automation-features/</guid><description>People that know me might be aware of the fact that i&amp;rsquo;m a strong proponent of using powerCLI, due to its power of allowing the simple yet powerful automation of single tasks (you should be using Orchestrator for recurring tasks, but even that can use powerCLI) as well as the great runbook scripting capatibility for new deployments, upgrades, migrations and disaster recovery.</description></item><item><title>Automating distributed firewall rule deployment with PowerNSX</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/automating-distributed-firewall-rule-deployment-with-powernsx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 12:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/automating-distributed-firewall-rule-deployment-with-powernsx/</guid><description>As part of a microsegmentation project, we&amp;rsquo;re also doing the full implementation of the DFW ruleset to isolate and categorize application tiers and inter-tier traffic. Since implementing these rules manually would be very labour-intensive and the risk of manual errors are always lurking, the obvious way would be to automate this.</description></item><item><title>NSX, Dynamic routing and VPC</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/nsx-dynamic-routing-and-vpc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 03:07:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/nsx-dynamic-routing-and-vpc/</guid><description>While the subject has come up quite a bit, it&amp;rsquo;s still mostly shrouded in mystery and getting a proper answer on what does and doesn&amp;rsquo;t work usually requires some shady voodoo rituals.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a powershell development environment for non-programmers</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/setting-up-a-powershell-development-environment-for-non-programmers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 10:33:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/setting-up-a-powershell-development-environment-for-non-programmers/</guid><description>In most of my projects, powershell and its vendor-specific modules such as VMware&amp;rsquo;s powercli is usually a necessity to work effectively. In addition, most customers appreciate it greatly if you can leave them with a handful of examples on how to run standard procedures through a script, even though it might not always be part of the deliverables.</description></item><item><title>/usr/bin/whoami</title><link>https://vxsan.com/posts/whoami/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 09:33:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/posts/whoami/</guid><description>About me # Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m Sjors, the author of this blog and the person you&amp;rsquo;re currently reading about. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in IT since 1999 in various functions, from support desk to frontend development, Cisco network engineering, Linux engineer and currently mainly focused on technical consultancy, specifically the design and implementation of VMware NSX.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vxsan.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vxsan.com/about/</guid><description>/usr/bin/whoami #</description></item></channel></rss>