<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NSX on</title><link>https://srobroek.github.io/categories/nsx/</link><description>Recent content in NSX on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright/><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 10:06:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srobroek.github.io/categories/nsx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running pre-boot, post-provisioning vRO workflows in vRA.</title><link>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/running-pre-boot-vro-workflows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 10:06:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/running-pre-boot-vro-workflows/</guid><description>Note: As this is more of a reminder for myself so i don&amp;rsquo;t forget next time, don&amp;rsquo;t expect too much fluff.
Last week i needed to demonstrate how to temporarily enable firewall rules using the NSX DFW for a customer use case that is pretty serious about zero trust policies.</description></item><item><title>Burn down your DFW onboarding with vRealize Log Insight</title><link>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/burn-down-your-dfw-onboarding-process-with-log-insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 08:05:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/burn-down-your-dfw-onboarding-process-with-log-insight/</guid><description>Currently i&amp;rsquo;m working on a NSX project involving a large amount of networks and a complicated firewall setup that needs to be migrated to NSX. Using tools such as vRealize Network insight for traffic flow insight helps a lot, but ultimately the DFW onboarding process needs to be SMART, and specifically the following:</description></item><item><title>Automated NSX DFW validation with PowerNSX</title><link>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/automated-nsx-dfw-validation-with-powernsx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 07:39:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/automated-nsx-dfw-validation-with-powernsx/</guid><description>For a project i&amp;rsquo;m currently working on, we need to provide a full end-to-end validation of the NSX routing, distributed firewall rules and VXLAN functionality. As the amount and complexity of firewall rules are quite significant, i&amp;rsquo;ve written a script that allows you to run and retrieve data from NSX Traceflow in an automated fashion, which can be found at https://bitbucket.</description></item><item><title>multi-backend SSL Passthrough Loadbalancing with VMware NSX</title><link>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/multi-backend-ssl-passthrough-loadbalancing-with-nsx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 06:24:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/multi-backend-ssl-passthrough-loadbalancing-with-nsx/</guid><description>Currently i&amp;rsquo;m working on a NSX project that involves automation of NSX loadbalancers to provide loadbalancing as a catalog item. Now, while i would normally prefer deploying dedicated loadbalancers on-demand, a big constraint in this environment is the fact that the ISP takes a significant time to configure the GSLB for new services, so on-demand loadbalancers go straight out of the window.</description></item><item><title>Automating distributed firewall rule deployment with PowerNSX</title><link>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/automating-distributed-firewall-rule-deployment-with-powernsx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 12:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/automating-distributed-firewall-rule-deployment-with-powernsx/</guid><description>As part of a microsegmentation project, we&amp;rsquo;re also doing the full implementation of the DFW ruleset to isolate and categorize application tiers and inter-tier traffic. Since implementing these rules manually would be very labour-intensive and the risk of manual errors are always lurking, the obvious way would be to automate this.</description></item><item><title>NSX, Dynamic routing and VPC</title><link>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/nsx-dynamic-routing-and-vpc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 03:07:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srobroek.github.io/posts/nsx-dynamic-routing-and-vpc/</guid><description>While the subject has come up quite a bit, it&amp;rsquo;s still mostly shrouded in mystery and getting a proper answer on what does and doesn&amp;rsquo;t work usually requires some shady voodoo rituals.</description></item></channel></rss>